Copy that.
收到
Thank you, sir.
谢谢您
Target secured.
任务完成
Our team's on their way back.
我们人在回来路上
Command Central, this is Patrol Unit 00638.
指挥部 这里是00638巡逻车
We're headed back. Over.
申请收队
Copy that.
收到
It's time.
你们可以开始了
Opening with a little pawn.
小兵开局
What's wrong?
怎么了
Probably nothing.
没事
I thought there was a glitch.
刚才我好像眼花了一下
Madam,
长官
Macao Asia Bank's vault alarm was tripped.
澳亚银行保险库自动报警系统被触发
CPSP Police received the alarm, too.
治安警察那边同样收到警报
Their patrol units are on the way.
已经通知巡逻小队赶过去
Where is their nearby patrol unit?
他们附近的伙计到了吗
They left two minutes ago.
两分钟前刚离开
They're on the bridge.
桥上无法掉头
ETA five minutes.
最快也得五分钟
Where's our people?
我们的人呢
Madam.
长官
Captain Wu Yaolei here.
我是伍耀磊
Alpha team in pursuit.
A队追缉中
Du Ping, activate S.P.A.I.S.
杜平 启动 S.P.A.I.S.
S.P.A.I.S. activated.
AI监踪系统 启动
Reverse tracking 4,328 Skyeye cameras
反向追踪银行三公里范围内
within 3 km of the bank.
四千三百二十八个天眼监控画面
Scanning suspicious vehicles.
可疑目标搜索定位中
Skyeye countertracking.
天眼反追踪
Got something.
有结果了
They're not after cash.
目标不是现金
What do you mean?
什么意思
They're empty-handed.
空着手呢
Madam, got them on Camera 120C,
长官 120C监控拍到他们了
exiting Liwan Roundabout, southbound.
正往荔湾环岛南向出口驶出
Direct all nearby patrol cars
让周边所有警力车辆
to cut off their escape route.
把劫匪的逃脱路线给我堵死
Yes, Madam.
收到
Attention, all units.
各单位注意
Suspect vehicle is a black MPV
现有伪装计程车的黑色
disguised as a taxi.
MPV疑犯车辆
Unit Charlie 2-5.
Unit Charlie 2-5.
proceed to the intersection of
立即前往地厘古工程师马路
Estr. do Eng. Trigo and Estr. de Cacilhas.
与松山西海边马路交汇处
Bravo 6, Estr. sul de Lychee intersection.
Bravo 6 前往荔枝路南口
Delta 9-2, standby at midsection of Estrada do Sul.
Delta 9-2 前往南山路中段
With Skyeye and Spice Girl,
天眼加辣妹
they've got nowhere to hide.
他们能跑哪去
Block off Rua do Campo.
把水坑尾给我堵上
Tap Seac Tunnel and Estr. do Cemiterio,
还有塔石隧道入口和西坟马路东段
Seal them off.
都给我封死
Madam,
长官
Spice Girl is against this plan.
辣妹不建议这个方案
All units, head to Estr. de Cacilhas,
各单位前往松山西海边马路
Prepare to intercept.
准备拦截
Not to intercept.
不是拦截
What's the problem?
指令有问题吗
Du Ping,
杜平
disable autonomous analysis and command.
关闭 S.P.A.I.S.自主分析权和指令权
Yes, ma'am.
收到
Alpha Teams 1 and 2,
Alpha Team 一组二组
go east to Dom Belchior Carneiro Street.
去高园街东向逆行
Unit 3, southeast to Tomas Vieira Street.
三组去新胜街往东南方向逆行
Unit 4, go north on Artilheiros Street.
四组经炮兵街 上北向镜湖马路
Box the bastards at Repouso Road.
把这帮混蛋给我堵死在镜湖大路口
Yes, ma’am.
收到
All units, split up.
各队 分开追击
Wu Yaolei.
伍耀磊
What are you doing?
干嘛呢
Arrest them.
伍耀磊 抓人
Come on？
听见了吗
We’re at Repouso Road.
已到达镜湖路口
No visual on suspect vehicle.
没看到疑犯车辆
What do you mean no visual?
什么叫没看到
It’s right there.
这不是就在那吗
Are you all blind?
都瞎了吗
Madam.
长官
Can you see me?
看到我了吗
What do we do now?
现在该怎么办
Pawn out.
小兵出局
Knight knight.
马线安全
Can I help you, sir?
先生 有什么可以帮到你
Latte.
拿铁
Larry, you lazy son of a bitch, get the door.
莱瑞 你个懒货 去开门
What?
干什么
Police.
警察
Sure about not going to the bank?
你确定不用去银行现场看一下
Why would I want to go?
我为什么要去
The paper with half of my password was stolen, right?
保险箱里写了一半密码的小本已经被偷走了
Right?
不是吗
They probably wouldn't act this fast.
不过他们应该没这么快动手
No, they want the other half.
不 他们想要另一半
They need the other half.
他们需要另一半
Without the other half,
没有另外一半
all of this would be for nothing.
他们就白忙活了
What exactly is cryptocurrency?
你说这加密货币到底什么东西
Money, sir.
钱啊 警官
Over 500 million HK dollars.
五个多亿
No answer at JH Digital Asset Management.
金辉数字资管一直没有人接电话
They may be doing it right now.
他们可能真动手了
Hi, Aoxing Tower security office.
您好 澳兴大厦保安室
Hello, sir.
您好
This is Polícia Judiciária Command Center.
这里是司警局刑侦指挥中心
We suspect that someone on the 4th floor
我们怀疑大厦四层的
at JH Digital Asset Management
金辉数字资产管理公司
is attempting to steal sensitive data.
有人正在非法窃取敏感资料
Please don't act on your own.
请不要擅自行动
What's the police's ETA?
警察多久能到
What's your ETA?
你们还有多久能到
Within five minutes.
五分钟之内
Understood.
好的 收到
Three minutes.
三分钟
Got it. Three minutes.
收到 三分钟
Found it.
找到了
Damn...
我去
So many files.
这么多文档
Copy them all.
全部拷走
Can't you transfer the money out yourself?
你的钱就不能自己转出来
Account passwords for cryptocurrency
加密货币的账户密码
consist of twelve English words,
是十二个英文单词
all randomly generated.
随机组成的
That's 2048 to the 12th power.
二千零四十八的十二次方种可能性
That's an algorithm behind it.
它背后是有公式算法的
You've no idea.
你知道那是怎么
Sit back.
坐回去
It's impossible to memorize.
就记不住嘛
Two minutes.
两分钟
Xin, what are you doing?
小辛 你干嘛呢
Just look around.
随便看看
Don’t touch anything else.
别碰其他东西
Lots of VIP clients.
不少大客户
Gordon D.
戈登 D
What is this?
这是什么
Digital encryption key.
数字密钥
It's Duan Zhihong.
是段志鸿啊
Who’s Duan Zhihong?
段志鸿是谁
CEO of Kuala Lumpur's biggest crypto exchange.
吉隆坡最大加密货币交易网站的CEO
He vanished with $1.5 billion USD,
卷了十五个亿美金跑了
then mysteriously turned up dead in Macau.
后来在澳门被人发现离奇死亡
People still think he faked his own death.
到现在都被人怀疑是假死
This digital key's firewall is
这个密钥的防火墙是
TAQ-LX-5 level.
TAQ-LX-5级别的
What does that mean?
什么东西
One level short of military-grade.
再高一级就是军用级别
Why is such an important key
这么贵重的密钥
hidden in a crappy server like this?
怎么会藏在这么一个破服务器里
I heard Duan's $1.5 billion
我听说段志鸿的十五亿美金
is still unaccounted for.
到现在都还下落不明
That's over HK$10 billion.
那是一百多亿港币
Copy everything.
全部拷走
We're out of time, Simon.
不可以 没时间了 熙蒙
Won't take long.
很快
Xin, we’re leaving.
小辛 快走了
Give me a minute.
一分钟 一分钟
There's no time.
没时间了
Go.
走
Heads down.
把头给我低下
Don't look.
别看
Police are at the entrance.
警察到门口了
Don’t panic.
别慌
What’s going on upstairs?
上面什么情况
Sorry.
不好意思
Hi, who are you?
您好 您是哪里的
Police.
警察
We have a report of a robbery.
接到资产管理公司报案
Suspects just left.
劫匪刚刚离开
Four males,
四名男性
early twenties.
约二十出头
Go Bishop.
象线撤离
Go.
追
Get them.
追 追
Song, cut them off.
阿翔 那边堵他们
Freeze.
别跑
Stop.
站住
Alpha 3 and4 have arrived.
A队三四组到达
Bravo 4 on-site.
B队四组到达现场
Bravo 1 and 2, watch the lobby.
B队一二组控制大厅
Bravo 3 and 4, block the exits.
三四组封锁大厦南北门
Bravo 3 on-site.
B队三组到达
Qiuguo, assist Forensics on the 4th floor.
何秋果 配合鉴定科四楼取证
Yes, sir.
是
Stop.
别跑
Don't move.
别动
Freeze.
不许动
Drop the gun.
把枪放下
Don't move.
别动
Freeze.
不许动
Put the gun down.
把枪放下
Don't worry about me, do your job.
别管我 做事
Captain Wu's been held hostage.
伍警官被劫持
They're going up.
他们上去了
Wynn Macau.
去永利
The boys,
弟弟们
may be...
可能
Wynn, let's go.
我说去永利
What are you waiting for?
还待着干什么
Captain.
磊哥
Wu Yaolei.
伍耀磊
Fake.
仿真枪
-Help me. -Pull.
-救命啊 -使点劲
They have parachutes.
他们有滑翔伞
Captain.
磊哥
Send reinforcements
让增援部队
to Wynn Macau.
去永利澳门
Go.
走
Captain, elevators are hacked.
伍警官 向上的电梯被他们黑客锁住了
How will you come down?
你怎么下来
I'm jumping.
跳下来
Stay where you are.
你不要过来
Wynn Macau, rooftop.
永利澳门的屋顶平台
You really jumped?
真跳下来了
Attention, all units.
各单位注意
Send backup to new target location.
支援车辆立即赶往新目标地点
Wynn Macau.
永利澳门
Assist with the arrest.
配合抓捕
I've called their security chief,
已经通知到永利澳门
Mathew Tab.
安保负责人Mathew Tab
Sit back.
坐回去
They're coming on the rooftop.
他们上天台了
Call for backup.
呼叫增援
They must have a plan B,
他们一定有后手
tell Tab to watch out.
告诉老谭别大意
This isn't that simple.
这事没那么简单
What?
你干嘛
What do you mean?
什么意思
How can they just vanish
什么叫进入酒店之后
from all the cameras?
就从监控里消失了
That's what they did.
确实不见了
You look like shit.
被揍这么惨
Where are they?
人呢
They're in the hotel.
他们进来了
Xin, the police have arrived.
小辛 警察到了
That's fast.
这么快
Rook route is dead.
车线出不去
Take the queen route.
走后线
How'd you let them run?
你怎么让他们跑了
They did not run, they flew.
没跑 飞了
Fifteen seconds.
十五秒
Ready for Queen.
后线准备
I need a location.
我需要位置
Looking for it.
正在找
Find them, and fast.
找到他们 快点
What's going on?
什么情况
Not us.
不是我这
What the hell happened to my cameras?
我的监控怎么了
Wynn's surveillance was remotely shut down.
永利澳门的监控系统被人远程入侵关闭了
Everyone.
所有人
Get moving.
移动搜索
Split up, eyes open.
化整为零
As long as they're still in here,
他们只要还在酒店里
they can't keep their faces hidden.
就不可能一直蒙着脸
Everyone,
所有人注意
turn on your body cameras.
打开你们的执法记录仪
Capture every face you come across.
把能看到的每一张脸全部都拍下来
Du Ping.
杜平
Operate S.P.A.I.S. manually.
人工操作S.P.A.I.S.
Run facial recognition on all live images
对执法记录仪实时画面
caught on body cameras.
进行面孔识别
On it.
收到
Find those without entry records,
找到没有进门记录的
starting with the staff area.
先从员工区找起
Don’t get caught on camera.
不能被拍到脸
Or we're screwed.
拍到就死了
I'm in.
我进来了
Tell me your whereabouts,
把你们的位置告诉我
I'll handle it from here.
接下来 一切听我的
King's move.
王的走位
Turn around.
转回去
Locker room.
到更衣室
Change.
换装
Excuse me, sir.
打扰下 先生
Sir.
先生
Alpha 2 is taking elevator MCS1 to Ground Floor.
A2二组乘坐MCS1电梯去往G层
Ray.
阿威
Turn around.
转身
Take the cart at your 10.
十点方向取车
Attention all units,
各小组注意
Suspects may have changed disguises.
疑犯很可能已经改变造型
Stay sharp, keep moving.
所有人移动搜捕
175 centimeters,
一七五公分
medium length hair,
中发
black and white hooded baseball jacket,
黑白拼接连帽棒球夹克
dark camouflage multi-pocket pants,
深色迷彩多袋裤
Backpack.
背包
He just headed to the cafeteria.
他刚刚往餐厅去了
Xin.
小辛
You’re blown.
你暴露了
Feng,
枫
burn that face.
废张脸
Help Xin.
帮小辛
Yes, sir.
收到
Song, the guy who just passed by.
宋智翔 刚刚走过去那个人
Now.
现在
He has no entry record.
他没有进门记录
What?
什么
There.
那 那
That's him.
在那呢
I got this one.
我看到耳环了
Song, go after the other guy.
阿翔 你去追另一个
Excuse me.
不好意思
Song, wipe the lens.
宋智翔 擦一擦你的镜头
Go get that one.
去抓那个
Go.
去
Move.
跟上
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Where is he?
人呢
The Wynn Prosperity Tree lobby is packed.
伍耀磊 吉祥树大厅多了很多游客
I thought the show is after 12.
吉祥树表演不是每天十二点之后吗
When there's a system upgrade,
不定期升级系统
they run a test show that morning.
会在当天上午进行一次测试
Find them.
分开找
Spread out.
散开 散开
Eyes peeled, stay sharp.
睁开眼睛 保持警惕
Over there.
那边 那边
They're posing as cops.
他们假扮警察
Checkmate.
将杀
It's all gone.
没有了
500 million.
五个亿
Not a penny left.
一毛都没了
Crypto is impossible to trace!
虚拟货币是追不回来的
You police are useless!
你们警察是干什么用的
They hacked us
他们利用黑客手段
and infiltrated the surveillance system.
入侵我们的监控系统
So...
以此
Without Skyeye,
没有这个天眼
we can't fight crimes anymore,
你们也不会抓人了
Is that it?
是吗
Before we had all this technology,
以前没有这些高科技的时候
how did the police do their jobs?
警察怎么做事的
It was my mistake.
这次是我的疏忽
I'll catch them next time.
下次一定抓到他们
Even if there's a next time,
就算有下一次
they'll probably still counter our every move.
我们的刑侦手段依然被他们牵制
So tell me...
你告诉我
What do we do?
怎么抓
If they stop now,
如果他们就此收手了
where's our breakthrough?
我们的突破口在哪里
Sorry, sir.
对不起 长官
What's the progress
网监这边
from cyber division?
有什么进展
We've patched the intrusion point and code bugs,
已经修复了入侵端口和代码漏洞
but no progress on reverse tracking.
但反向追踪没有结果
To catch a cunning fox,
对付狡猾的狐狸
we need an experienced hunter.
需要一个老猎手
Are you suggesting
你是说
bringing back Wong?
把黄德忠找来
I know he's your old boss.
我知道他是你的老上司
But this is the era of A.I. tracking.
但现在是 AI 监踪时代
And they've just exploited its weakness.
但这次还是被罪犯抓到漏洞了
There are flaws in the network
网络有漏洞
and surveillance equipment,
我们的监听设备有漏洞
but S.P.A.I.S. is flawless.
但S.P.A.I.S.没有漏洞
You stopped S.P.A.I.S. learning from real operations.
如果不是你总不让它在实战中学习
You let your phone tell you how to do your job?
你抓贼的时候会让手机告诉你怎么做事吗
That doesn't mean bringing in a fossil
那你现在搬块化石出来
will fix the police's image.
警队的形象还要不要了
Captain.
伍耀磊
I don't care if we use fossil or Spice Girl,
我不管你用化石还是辣妹
Find them, catch them.
找到他们 抓到他们
Do your job.
做好你的事
Jeez, Guoguo,
我的天 果果
have you seen Wong's file?
他们刚发来的黄德忠资料你看到没
He's incredible.
不得了
Multiple commendations.
这是拿了几次英勇奖章
Special Ops all-around champion.
特种侦查个人全能冠军
Police hand-to-hand combat champion.
警队格斗冠军
Five years straight!
连续五年
Proficient in firearms,
精通射击
surveillance,
跟踪
infiltration,
渗透
intelligence gathering.
情报搜集
He’s gone undercover in drug cartels
曾卧底毒贩集团
and organ trafficking rings.
黑帮器官买卖集团
Restrained, low-profile.
为人克制低调
Skilled at blending in.
善于隐藏
Hobby...
个人爱好
Making up call signs.
起代号
This says his career's single stain is
这里说职业生涯唯一污点
a major personal mistake that killed
曾因个人重大失误造成拍档
his partner.
殉职
Write down which dog pees and poos first.
你一会记得注意一下哪只先尿尿拉臭
Is that really him?
这是他吗
Hi.
喂
Have you find it?
你找到没
Nope.
还没有
Everyone else is on the field for the big case
这么大案子别人都上一线了
and I have no idea what I’m doing.
我一天天的都不知道自己在干嘛
Observing someone's retirement?
观摩退休生活吗
Be patient.
你别急嘛
Maybe captain's looking out for you.
队长是有意照顾你的也说不定
Perhaps we're not ready for the field yet.
可能现在的确还没有到需要咱们上一线
I’ll call you later.
我晚点跟你说
A training drill on a geezer like me?
你是在拿我老头子练手吗
Come again?
先生您说什么
Why are you following me?
为什么跟踪我
You're mistaking me for someone else.
先生您认错人了吧
You don’t know me?
你不认识我
I don't.
不认识
Do you need something?
您有什么事吗
You weren't tailing me in a jacket in reverse?
刚刚反穿外套跟踪我的不是你
Can you sit elsewhere?
麻烦您坐到旁边去
Sorry.
不好意思
It’s fine.
没事
At 14:23, you reached the first target,
今天下午两点二十三分到达第一现场
which was the pet shop,
也就是宠物店的门口
Up to now,
到刚刚
you've tailed me for 4 hours and 17 minutes.
一共跟踪了我四个小时十七分钟
You changed your outfit three times,
中间你换了三次造型
and stopped 9 times to jot notes.
停下来记笔记九次
On the bus,
公交车上
you had a colleague help you.
还有同事跟你配合监视
Watch it.
小心点
Pardon me.
不好意思
Am I right, He Qiuguo?
对不对 何秋果
That look
你这个表情
just gave you away.
不就露馅了吗
You remember me,
您还记得我
Uncle Wong.
黄叔叔
We haven't met since I was 8.
上次见面还是八岁那会
I heard you joined the force
听说你当司警了
and inherited your father's badge number.
继承你爸爸的警号
He would be proud.
他会骄傲的
How'd you know when I was at the pet shop?
您怎么知道我几点到的宠物店门口
I have a few pointers.
那我就要批评你了
First of all,
第一
never throw away your notes.
笔记不能扔掉
Second,
第二
dog walking time,
遛狗
leaving work,
下班
and boarding the bus
上车时间
were all inaccurate.
都不准确
The order of dogs pee and poo is a mess.
尿尿拉臭顺序错得离谱
Which one was the sixth to poop?
第六只拉臭的是哪只
Al Paca-paca,
杨驼驼
the poodle.
那个贵宾
It'd be my mistake if I didn't pick it up.
不捡呢 是我的疏忽
Confuse my memory if I did.
捡呢 混扰我的记忆
Not bad.
不错
You said my colleague was on the bus.
您说车上有我的同事
Why do you say that?
凭什么这么说
Oh, I see.
明白了
This isn't training.
不是练手
You're checking
是想看看我黄德忠
if I’ve still got it.
尚能饭否
You two tailed me for 4 hours at that skill level.
就你们这个水平还单组跟我四个小时
Who gave you the confidence?
谁给你们的这个自信
Long time no see, Officer Wong.
好久不见 黄警官
This is inspector Wu Yaolei.
这位是伍耀磊督察
Let me do it.
我来吧
No.
不用
You call yourself a cop?
怎么当警察的
No wonder I felt that old man touched me.
我就觉得那老头摸了我一下
Sound like you're proud of it.
你还觉得挺荣幸的是吗
So the partner
跟他一起执行任务
who died on duty...
牺牲的是
That was your dad?
你老爸
Back off.
不用
These are footage we gathered from the scene.
这是目前搜集到的一些现场视频
This footage is
这段
Wynn's feed before hackers cut it.
是永利监控被黑客掐断前的画面
Just play the last 15 seconds, please.
就放最后的十五秒 谢谢
Play it again.
再来一遍
Stop.
停
How did you spot them?
你怎么发现的
They peeked at cameras when they entered.
就他们几个人一出现 先找监控
They must have scouted beforehand
应该提前踩过点
and knew where the cameras were.
知道监控在哪
Why'd they look, then?
那为什么还要找
To see if the cameras were still on.
确认监控是否还开着
Once the cameras were cut,
监控一断
they changed their disguises.
应该改造型了吧
Didn’t they?
是改了吧
Xiwang.
哥
Old man pissed over the change of plans?
擅改计划 老头子是不是气坏了
What do you think?
你觉得呢
Go console him.
快去哄哄老爷子吧
Godfather...
干爹
We all made it back safely.
弟弟们都安全回来了
Hell of a day, wasn't it?
今天真的是有惊无险
I can explain.
听我解释
You almost got everyone killed.
你差点害死我们所有的人
That wasn’t part of the plan.
这不是我们的计划
But we got the job done.
结果是好的呀
With a bonus, no less.
而且还有意外收获
What bonus?
什么收获
I only saw mistakes.
全是意外
All these years,
这么多年
I've never been caught on camera.
都没给人拍过
Now I have,
就因为你
you little shit!
这个小王八蛋
It'll be fine, I'll handle it.
就算被拍了不是还有我吗
You're a little shit too.
你也是王八蛋
Just let go.
你就放手
Let us call the shots for once.
放手让我们去做吧
Let go?
放手
Can you tell me
那你能告诉我
what I should be scared of now?
我现在该怕的是什么
You wouldn't understand it anyway.
我就是说了你可能也听不懂
Let me tell you
让你们知道
what you should fear.
你们该害怕什么
Godfather.
干爹
Even you're turning on me.
连你都要反我
It's our fault.
我们错了
For decades, no one's had a photo of me.
老子几十年没被人拍过
That's changed because of you shitheads.
就因为你这个小王八蛋
Don't be mad.
消消气
That's more than 10 billion sweet HKD.
干爹 那可是一百多亿港币
With this money,
有了这笔钱
we can all live our dreams.
我们都能够过上自己想要的生活
Shut it. You know how deep you were in danger?
闭嘴 你们知道今天有多危险吗
That tall guy.
这个高个儿的那个
The walking lightning rod changed outfits.
行走的避雷针 变模样了
Eyes on the screen.
大家看荧幕
Lightning Rod.
避雷针
Remember his characteristics.
记住了
This guy, grinding his teeth.
咬着后槽牙那个
Number 2, number 2.
二号 二号
Found the one with the earrings.
发现戴耳环那个
That's right.
没错
That's him.
就是他
Send it.
发
On the screen,
荧幕上
that's Lil Puppy no. 2.
小奶狗二号
Lightning Rod 3 spotted,
避雷针三号出现
not very clear though.
但我这个不太清楚
I've got a decent shot over here.
我这里有拍到还可以的
Very good, very good.
非常好 非常好
Pretty Face number 2,
大漂亮二号
wearing a small mustache.
贴了个小胡子
Got it.
收到
I got Pretty Face number 3.
发现大漂亮三号
The squatting one.
蹲着那个
He changed disguises.
改造型了
How many fake mustaches does he have?
到底揣了多少胡子在兜里
Sir, I think this one is...
黄警官 这个应该是
Pretty Face number 4.
大漂亮四号
I've seen this coat somewhere.
这件外套我在哪见过
Someone gave it to him!
有人把外套给他了
Everybody, listen up.
大家听好了
There's one more person.
还有一个人
Cast everything you find
把刚刚的发现
to the main screen.
发到那个荧幕上
Yes, sir.
是
Police.
警察
Sorry.
不好意思
Xiwang.
阿旺
You saved my life once.
你救过我的命
I value this life very much.
这条命我很珍惜
I don't want anything to happen to you all.
但是我不想看到你们出任何事
Got that?
知道吗
Got it.
明白
We're with you,
我们和你
live or die.
同生共死
I don't want to die.
我不想死
I want all of us to enjoy our lives.
我要我们都好好地活着
Ms. Sun, the lobby café barista,
澳兴大厦大堂吧服务员孙某
took this photo that afternoon.
于案发当日拍下了这张照片
This is very likely the fifth person at Wynn.
这极有可能就是出现在永利的第五个人
Do we have any idea
这个人身份
of his identity?
搞清楚没有
Sorry sir, not yet.
对不起 长官 暂时还没有
In the late 80s,
80年代末
there was a wanted foreign ex-special force
有个外号叫影子的通缉犯
known as "The Shadow".
是外籍退伍的侦察兵
He served in an elite assassination squad.
服役期间隶属特工部队最精锐的暗杀小组
During the war, he disguised himself
曾经战场上数次伪装
to infiltrate military and political targets.
渗透到敌方军政目标身边
His kills were executed up close with a knife.
全部都是用匕首近身击杀
And he always got away.
并成功逃脱
Later, he fled here to seek greater wealth.
后来为了谋取更大财富流窜到这边
He planned more than a dozen bank heists
策划过十几起银行抢劫
and evaded three manhunts
三次逃避过警方的追捕
before vanishing without a trace in 1999.
九九年就神秘消失了
This guy could be the Shadow
这家伙会不会是
coming out of retirement.
重出江湖的影子
I remember him.
我记得他
What's your next step?
你们下一步什么计划
This photo isn't enough for facial recognition.
仅凭这张照片没办法进行人脸识别
We plan to increase manpower
我们计划增调人手
for a comprehensive sweep.
单点布控和地毯式排查
Area?
区域呢
We have few shots of his accomplice's vehicle.
这辆同伙车被拍到次数极少
These were all taken in the Old Town area.
仅有的这些都在旧城一带
It’s a large area.
范围很大
I suggest a two-pronged approach.
我建议双管齐下
Conduct an open sweep for diversion
明面上常规排查
while dispatching a covert surveillance team.
暗中让跟踪队潜伏搜捕
Officer Wong.
黄警官
There’s no covert surveillance team anymore.
已经没有跟踪队了
Not anymore?
没了吗
With today's surveillance network and A.I.,
如今的天眼网络和人工智能
traditional covert surveillance teams
让这个传统跟踪队的作业
are hardly ever needed.
很少派上用场
Small suggestion
我的一个
for ground surveillance.
粗浅建议
You should use your most inconspicuous officers.
布控要用你们当中气质最普通
Preferably ones suspects haven't seen before.
最好没被这个家伙见过脸的
Officer Wong,
黄警官
why don't you help us set up a temporary team?
你来帮临时组建跟踪队怎么样
A covert team put together last-minute
我觉得临时组建难成体系
won’t be as effective as
不如单点布控
a comprehensive approach.
隐蔽性更好
Guoguo.
小果子
Stay in your lane out there.
到时候你们就负责布控盯梢
Leave the arresting to us.
抓人我们来
Remember that.
记住啦
Guoguo can show off all she wants.
小果子练练身手碍着你了
I'm just worried that showing off will get to her head
我是怕她到时候一上一线逞能
and let them slip away again.
再让人给跑了
Why did someone so tiny become a cop?
这小身板当什么刑警
Her old man was a cop.
人家老爸就是刑警
Doesn’t she know
但她不知道
she's just a poster child?
自己就是我们警队的宣传物料吗
Can't even crack a smile.
还没个笑脸
What business is it of yours that I’m a cop?
我当刑警碍你们什么事了
I earned my spot in the Police Force.
我凭我自己本事当上的刑警
How dare you.
瞧不起谁
Don't forget, it was you idiots who let them get away.
别忘了让他们跑了的是你们这帮笨蛋
Com'on, I'm the suspect.
来 我是贼
Catch me.
抓我
Com'on.
抓啊
Field agent? Yeah, right.
想上一线 你凭什么
Come on.
用力
Com'on, get him.
-用力 -给劲
In a place like the detective squad,
刑警队这种地方
a little spar will earn you respect.
在家动动手
They'll watch your back out there.
在外面可以换命
No one in this place thinks
这种地方压根没人觉得
a woman could be the first to kick down a door.
第一个踹门冲进去的可以是个女的
The first one can catch a bullet, too.
第一个冲进去的可要挨子弹的
So what?
有什么不可以
I'm not afraid to die.
我不怕死
But they don't want you to die.
他们是怕你死
My life isn’t their concern.
我的命他们管得着吗
They do care about their colleagues' lives.
同僚的命他们不管的话
No one sees me as a colleague.
这没人拿我当同僚
Old friend...
兄弟
Guoguo's all grown up.
果果大了
She's just like you.
跟你很像
But I can tell she's not happy in the squad.
但是我看得出来她在刑警队不开心
That short fuse of hers
像她这个脾气
might get her in trouble
如果上一线
out on the field.
会出事的
Freeze. Police.
别动 警察
Rest assured.
不过你放心
I'll look after her.
我会看着她的
I'll do it.
我来吧
I'll train a covert surveillance team.
我来组建跟踪队
Let's catch him.
捉拿影子
How nice of Captain Wu to send so many.
伍队长够大方的 给我这么多人
Thank you. Goodbye.
谢谢 不用你了
You look like a cop.
太像警察了
Thanks.
谢谢
We're dealing with an old fox.
我们要对付的是一只老狐狸
An old-school thief.
一个老派的贼
That's why
所以
I'm going to train you
我要教会你们
to become old-school hunters.
当老派的猎手
Come.
来
During surveillance,
执行跟踪任务
develop an instinct to watch and memorize.
一定要养成看和记的本能
One glance.
看
That's all you get.
只看一眼
Focus on key characteristics.
抓重点看
Remember prominent and permanent features.
要学会瞬间留意突出且不变特征
I had my hands on my hips just now.
刚刚我叉着腰
Which two fingers
哪两根手指
were in my belt loops?
插在裤袢里
Left forefinger.
左手食指
Right middle finger.
右手中指
A surveillance team is an entity.
跟踪队是个体系
It takes every member
我们所有人在一起
to complete a mission.
才能把任务完成
Let's go.
出发
Guoguo.
果果
Get in.
这边
Starting today, you need to blend into the city.
从今天开始你们就要彻底融入这个城市
Let's put theory into action.
我们以战代练
Doghead calling Animal Paradise.
狗头呼叫萌宠乐园
Officer Wong,
黄警官
what did you say?
你说什么
Doghead.
狗头
That's me.
我
My call sign.
代号狗头
Adorable Unit's on site.
萌宠小队到达现场
I'll give your call signs now.
下面我来公布一下代号
Liu, you're Al Paca-paca.
刘锦肖 杨驼驼
Can I get another one?
我能换一个吗
I'll make it simpler.
简单一点
Alpaca.
叫羊驼
Okay.
好吧
Wanwan...
狄婉婉
You're Tofu.
豆花
Yang Zhiwei...
杨志伟
Rice Noodles.
肠粉
Ting...
唐婷
Pudding.
布丁
Sun Xu....
孙旭
Potstickers.
锅贴
Liao Qihang...
廖启航
Eggy.
培根蛋
Qiao Weidong...
乔卫东
Lucky.
旺财
Song Keyu...
宋克玉
Pork Bun.
猪扒包
Isn't that body shaming?
有点身材歧视了吧
It's a local specialty.
就地取材
This is a foodie squad.
这是菜单小队
Better than my old unit.
比我们当年好多了
He Qiuguo...
何秋果
Little Flower Piggy.
小花猪
Can I change it?
能换吗
I'll drop "Little".
那把小去掉
Then drop "Flower".
那还是去掉花吧
Patience.
别急
You're my ace in the hole.
你是我的王牌
Like I believe you.
我信你个鬼
It's fine.
没事
I'm used to being benched.
冷板凳我坐惯了
Boss,
老板
how much for this?
你看下这个值多少钱
Where'd you get this?
哪弄来的
None of your business.
不关你事
Pay her and send her off.
掏钱让她走
Hey...
喂 喂
Don't stare like they're suspects.
别看每个人都像看犯人一样
Pull over.
前面停一下
Are you really here?
你是出现了吗
This is your third time
你这是第三次
in the same spot
在同样的地方
in the same outfit
穿同样的衣服
using the same hand
同一只手
to drink the same way.
做同样喝水的动作
Your water
你的水位
is stuck at the same amount.
永远在同一个位置
I'm worried I'd need to pee.
我这不是怕喝多了上厕所嘛
Dehydration kills you too.
你就不怕脱水挂掉吗
Drink.
喝
There's 10 billion at stake.
就是因为有一百个亿
Once we get it,
拿回来了
we're set for life.
就我们都可以退休
It's just one last time.
就冒一次险而已
That's what you all think,
这就是你们的想法
isnt it?
是不是
Money isn't everything.
钱不是最重要的
Freedom is.
自由才是
Different time,
时代不同
different game.
玩法不同
If I let you plan
如果下回的事
the next mission...
让你来计划
You know what you're doing?
你有把握吗
Simon.
熙蒙
Dad.
老爸
Xiwang
熙旺
You've grown so much.
长高了
Come.
来来来
Come on.
来
Thanks, daddy!
谢谢爸爸
I have to leave for a while.
老爸要离开一阵子
Take good care of your brothers.
照顾好弟弟们
I’ll come back for you boys.
老爸会回来看你们的
Duan stashed 1.5 billion USD worth of crypto.
储存段志鸿那笔价值十五亿美金
The server location has been found.
加密货币的服务器位置找到了
We already have the decryption key,
虽然我们已经有了密钥
but the digital vault is hard to access.
但数字金库的位置很难接近
Simon's hiding at the orphanage,
熙蒙躲在孤儿院
making plans right now
正在做计划
Good place to hide.
那里很好
It holds a lot of memories.
而且有很多回忆
I know you're all tired,
我知道你们很累
but stay focused.
都打起精神来
Don't want a coffee?
你不喝啊
Get a pick-me-up.
提提神
Do I look tired to you?
我看上去很累吗
Have you thought about
有没有想过
killing me?
把我做掉
Then you can split my share.
把我那一份也都给分了
How could we, Godfather?
怎么可能 干爹
I'm old anyway.
反正我已经老了
I'll just be in your way.
又是碍手碍脚的
Am I right?
不是吗
Why'd you say
你什么意思
I'm your ace in the hole?
我是你的王牌
Are you gaslighting me?
职场PUA吗
Gas what?
什么A
If anyone even considers that,
谁敢这么想
I'll kill him.
我杀了他
The knife was already in your hand.
刀已经在手了
You think I didn't see that?
你以为我没看见
Am I not good enough?
是我哪里做的不好吗
You think I need special treatment, too?
还是说你也觉得我需要被特殊对待
No.
没有
You're fine.
没有不好
You don't need special treatment.
你也不需要特殊对待
When the knife's in your hand...
刀已经在手了
Don't blink.
就不要犹豫
Be forceful,
使点劲
or it wouldn't be a clean shave.
要不然刮不干净
Then why is everyone on the field
那为什么大家都在外边执行任务
and I'm sitting here, getting you coffee?
但我只能坐在这里给你买咖啡
You just really want to...
你就这么想
Yes.
想
I really want to.
很想
But I need you here right now.
可我现在需要你留在车上
Be my surveillance partner.
好好做我的监视搭子
That's an order.
这是命令
Yes, sir.
收到
Brother,
哥
if Xin hadn't held the old man back,
老头子那一刀如果不是小辛拉着
he would've stabbed me.
他真的会扎下来
He really meant to kill me.
他真的想杀我
Is it really that good?
真有那么好吃吗
It's just luncheon meat and egg noodles.
只是一个餐蛋面而已
Yours is much better than the diners'.
你做的比外边好吃多了
When I was your age,
我在你们这个年纪的时候
all I thought about was
每天只能想
how to stay alive on the battlefield.
怎么从战场上活下来
I envy that you boys can dream of anything
真羡慕你们现在什么都可以想
and dare to dream anything.
什么都敢想
All I want
我只是想
is a life in peace
早点过上安稳的日子
with all my brothers together.
和大家生活在一块
Not scattered, like now.
不想各过各的
All these years,
这些年
in order to look after me,
为了照顾我
you sacrificed spending time with your brothers.
你错过了很多跟弟弟们一块的时光
Since the day we met,
从我们认识的那天开始
you’ve been protecting me.
你就在照顾我
When all those cops were after me,
多少警察在抓我
I couldn't believe
没想到
a little beggar like you
是你这个小叫花子
would save me.
救了我
Then you risked your life
可后来您拿命换钱
to keep the bankrupt orphanage alive.
养着破产的福利院
Without you,
如果没有您的话
we’d have starved to death.
我们早就饿死了
Eat mine, too.
把我这碗也吃了吧
Out of all the kids,
在小孩当中
you’re the one I care about the most.
我最心疼的就是你
Because you’re just like me.
因为我觉得你很像我
Simon is more like you.
熙蒙更像
If that is so...
那么
He could be very dangerous.
他就是一个很危险的人物
Eggy and Tofu,
培根蛋 豆花
your date's over.
约会结束了
Get changed and get to Point E.
换装去E点
Pudding.
布丁
Change.
换装
Point B.
B点
Pork Bun.
猪扒包
Point A.
去A点
Something's been feeling off lately.
最近我老感觉哪里不太对
Stay away
这阵子
for a while.
你就不要再来了
I can take care of myself.
我自己懂得照顾自己
Come back to the car.
立刻回到车上来
Call the police.
马上报警
I am the police.
我就是警察
Help.
救命啊
Leave them alone.
放开她们
Get lost.
都给我滚
You're pretty cute, little missy.
这个小妹妹也挺可爱的嘛
Who are you?
你谁啊
Go.
快走
Let's go.
走了
Drive.
开车
Systems off.
关机
Do you know you're on a mission?
你知不知道你在执行任务
Protecting civilians is a cop’s mission.
保护市民就是警察的任务
At the right place
得分场合
and the right time.
分时间
You're on an active mission.
你是在执行任务
What's the mission?
什么任务
Operation Dinner for Officer Wong?
给黄警官买晚餐任务吗
Sorry, I failed the mission.
对不起 任务失败了
Listen carefully.
你听清楚了
You are on a covert surveillance mission.
你的任务是潜伏搜捕
You cannot blow your cover, no matter what.
任何情况之下都不能暴露你的身份
I didn't blow shit.
我没暴露
You reached for your badge.
你摸一下证件
If the Shadow saw that, it’s all over.
给影子看见我们就完蛋了
And where is he?
影子 影子在哪呢
We’ve been wandering for weeks.
转半个月了吧
It's time we actually do some real work.
是不是该干点正事了
This is real work.
这就是正事
It's only been two weeks.
才半个月
Do you know how long our longest mission was?
你知道我们执行任务最长一次多久吗
Eight months.
八个月
I know.
对啊
Then what?
然后呢
My father died because of you.
因为你 我爸牺牲了
The drug dealer escaped.
毒贩跑了
Do you know I hadn't seen him
你知不知道在他死之前
for over a year before he died?!
我已经一年多没有见过他了
It was all my fault.
就是因为我
I...
我
You know what I did that day?
你知道我跑哪去了吗
I did what you did.
就跟你刚才一样
What a cute kid.
好可爱的小朋友
I have bubbles right here.
我这有泡泡好玩
Do you like bubbles?
你要不要玩
Yes
要
Let's play in the van, shall we?
那我们上车上去玩好不好
We've got lots of toys inside.
车上有好多好玩的
Shall we?
好不好
What?
你干嘛
-Put the kid down. -Get lost.
-把孩子放下 -起开
Who are you?
你谁呀
Put the kid down.
我让你把孩子放下
Police.
警察
Don't move.
老实点
So what?
警察了不起啊
Let’s see your badge.
你证件呢 拿出来看一下
Police.
警察 别动
My recklessness
是我的愚蠢
got your father killed.
导致你爸爸牺牲
But you saved that child.
可你救了那个孩子
I didn't.
没有
The traffickers escaped in the chaos.
人贩子趁乱跑了
Did they ever find the child?
那孩子后来找到了吗
I don't know.
不知道
As police officers,
我们做警察的
we have to learn to stay rational.
终归都要学会狠下心来
Follow discipline.
服从理智
Execute orders.
执行任务
Better to have regrets
可能会后悔
than to make mistakes.
不会犯错
Because that's our duty.
因为职责所在
Possible sighting of the Shadow.
疑似影子出现
Mercado Rua de Oeste.
宝西大街菜市场
Blue sweater jacket.
蓝色毛衫外套
Grey pants.
灰色裤子
Wearing a brown beret.
棕色扁帽
Could be wearing glasses.
疑似佩戴眼镜
Everyone, change outfits.
所有人立刻换装
Prepare to ID him.
准备确认
All units, be advised.
各单位注意
Shadow spotted.
发现影子踪迹
Monitoring the market.
菜市场监控
Adorable Unit en route.
萌宠小队出发
Alpaca, Potsticker, east.
羊驼 锅贴 东
Eggy, Tofu, west.
培根蛋 豆花 西
Lucky, Rice Roll, south.
旺财 肠粉 南
Pudding, Pork Bun, north.
布丁 猪扒包 北
The Shadow may have seen you before.
影子可能在街上见过你们的脸
A pro like him doesn't forget.
这种高手扫过一眼就不会忘
He'll be vigilant the second time
第二次看见会警惕
and get suspicious.
靠近了会起疑
Maintain a two-unit distance.
保持两个单位的距离
Piggy.
小猪
ID him up close.
近身确认的任务交给你了
He hasn't seen your face.
他没见过你的脸
Small suggestion for ground surveillance.
我的一个粗浅建议
You should use your most inconspicuous officers.
布控要用你们当中气质最普通
Preferably ones suspects haven't seen before.
最好没被这个家伙见过脸的
Go.
去吧
Slow down.
走慢点
Maintain distance.
保持距离
Doghead calling Animal Paradise.
狗头呼叫萌宠乐园
Adorable Unit's on site.
萌宠小队到达现场
Alpaca.
羊驼
Approach the fruit stall on the west.
靠近西侧水果摊位置
Walk slowly.
慢慢走
Don't rush.
别着急
Our mission is to ID the target.
这次的任务就是确认目标
Don't spook the Shadow.
千万不要惊扰到影子
Relax. Be natural.
放松放松 自然一点
He's a pro.
他是高手
No room for negligence.
不能犯错
Potsticker, east exit.
锅贴 去东口
Copy.
收到
Pork Bun, stand by at the footbridge.
猪扒包 你到天桥就位
Pudding, don't get too close.
布丁 不要太近
Walk away.
自然走开
Alpaca.
羊驼
Can you ID him?
你有没有机会确认
Negative.
看不见正脸
Can't see his face.
一直有遮挡
Can't confirm.
无法确认
We may be able to see his face.
有机会确认影子正脸
Eggy, Shadow might've seen you at Aoxing.
培根蛋 影子在澳兴大厦见过你的脸
Don’t turn.
别转身
Tofu, well done.
豆花 干得漂亮
Piggy, it's on you.
小猪 靠你了
Be careful.
小心一点
I'll get closer to him.
我再离他近一点
Piggy, you might get blown.
小猪 你可能会被他发现的
I know. I have an idea.
我知道了 我有办法
It’s him.
是他
Confirmed.
确认
Hand down.
把手放下来
Don't move the camera.
不要动监控
All units, positive ID on the Shadow.
各单位注意 影子身份确认
Adorable Unit, change and stand by.
萌宠小队继续跟踪
Maintain cover.
注意隐蔽
Everyone, good job.
所有人 干的漂亮
Target confirmed.
目标确认
All units, do not breach 3 blocks perimeter.
所有小组 保持三条街以上距离
I repeat.
重复一遍
Do not approach target area.
不要接近目标区域
Be advised, no siren.
注意 别开警笛
The target has entered a blind spot.
目标进入监控盲区
Lucky, you're up.
旺财 你上
Potsticker, tail him.
锅贴 跟着他
Not too close.
别跟太近
The bastard won't get away.
老家伙跑不掉的
Shadow's headed to Changning Apartments.
影子往昌宁公寓方向去了
The blocks are connected inside.
大楼内部是连着的
There are hundreds of flats.
好几百户呢
If we don't get his flat number,
这次查不到门牌号
there won't be a next time.
再想查就难了
The Shadow's in Block C, Unit 1.
影子进入昌宁公寓三栋一单元
No camera inside the building.
大楼内部没有监控
We'll lose him in an elevator.
让他进电梯就麻烦了
Pull over.
停车
Adorables.
跟踪队
They are too far away.
他们距离太远了
Adorable unit, come in.
跟踪队回答我
I'm too far away to catch up.
我在天桥上 太远了无法跟进
Potsticker cannot follow.
锅贴也无法跟进
Eggy cannot follow.
培根蛋无法跟进
I’ll go.
我来
Piggy can follow.
小猪可以跟进
I'm in.
我进来了
Top floor.
按顶层
What are you doing?
你干嘛啊
Will you listen to me or not?
我的话你听不听
What?
什么啊
Dating behind my back.
偷偷谈恋爱
My friend caught you, you know.
被人发现了你知不知道
What floor?
你几楼
I forgot something.
忘了点事
You two go ahead.
先送你们
Getting all dolled up now?
谈恋爱就臭美了
I knew you'd lose your earrings
听这么大的耳机还带耳环
with those big earphones on.
都不够你丢的
Com'on, leave me alone.
行了 少管我
See this?
你看看
They stop listening when they grow up.
现在的孩子说什么都没用
All they do is go against their parents.
各种跟父母对着干
They're grown-ups with minds of their own.
长大了 总会有自己的想法
What can a father do?
当爸的没得选
You're terribly open-minded.
你倒看得开
Otherwise, they’ll start
要不然将来有事
hiding things from you.
她就会开始瞒着你
Your Aunt Kandam said that guy looks like an alpaca.
你王钢蛋阿姨说那货长得跟羊驼似的
Is that why you’re hiding him from me?
你就为这个瞒着我
Who?
哪个
The guy you’re dating.
你约会那个
What's wrong with looking like a alpaca?
长得像羊驼怎么了
Alpacas are cute.
我觉得挺好
He’s actually really handsome, okay?
人家明明长得很帅的 好吧
That's been sitting for days.
这都放了好几天了
Why'd you buy it?
你还买
Got a camera signal.
有摄像头启动了
It's all the same in the stomach.
吃到肚子都一样
Here.
来
Want one?
来一个
Check his background.
查他底细
Roger that.
收到
Shadow's face acquired.
取得影子面部信息
Caught on camera.
正面被拍到
How can you just spit that out?
怎么往电梯里吐
The janitors will clean it up.
物业会打理
Look, it's fine.
你看多干净
I hope you’ll marry into
你老爸是希望有一天
a rich family someday.
你嫁入豪门望族的
Ever seen a rich father-in-law
那你见过哪个豪门岳父
behave this uncivilized?
像你这样的没素质
One bad apple can't drag a family down.
豪门素质也不是岳父一个人可以拖垮的
Will you be better to yourself?
你以后可以对自己好点吗
Buy some fresh fruits.
买点新鲜的苹果
I'm saving up for you.
我省吃俭用都是为了你
Not again.
又来了
Bye.
再见
So who's courting who now?
你们两个到底谁追谁
None of your business.
关你什么事
You have such a bad temper.
你脾气那么臭
What does he see in you?
他怎么会喜欢你呢
Keep walking.
继续走
I have a great temper.
我脾气好得很
Now what?
现在怎么办
Follow me.
跟着我走
What's his zodiac?
他什么星座的
What's it to you?
你问这个干嘛
To see if he is compatiable with me.
我看看跟我合不合
You're not serious.
要你管
Get the package.
拿快递
I'm amazed how nosy you can be.
你一天到晚挺八卦呀
You buy so much stuff.
又买那么多东西
Police.
警察
Close the door.
关门
We need this flat, please move out.
我们今晚要住这 你搬出去
Police business.
执行任务
Eighth floor.
八层
802, got it.
八零二 有了
Shadow lives in Channing apartment,
影子住在昌宁公寓
C block, unit 1, 802. Solid intel.
C栋楼一号门八零二室 可靠情报
Pick it up.
捡啊
What's that sound?
这是什么声音
Popping bubble wrap?
好像是在捏气泡膜
Is it OCD?
强迫症吗
It's unsolvable.
这题无解
No wonder it's torn.
怪不得给撕了
Weird.
奇怪
They’re all wrong.
都是错的
In the past, the Shadow would always
以往影子做完案
disappear after a job
都会立刻溜走
and remains silent for a while.
并沉寂很长一阵子
He's a man of principle.
他一直很有原则
This time, he broke his own protocol.
这次他变得不谨慎
What's happening?
发生了什么
If I’m not mistaken,
没估错的话
my guess is
我们应该
we've spooked him.
已经惊动他了
Whatever he wants to play,
看他想怎么玩
we'll play with him.
我们陪他玩
Finally stopped buying rotten apples?
终于不买烂苹果
What a coincidence.
这么巧
How much?
怎么卖
$3.70.
三块七
Prices have gone up.
涨价喽
It's all right.
还好
Twenty cents.
两毛
Everything's more expensive now.
什么都涨了
This one.
老板
Thanks.
谢谢
That stall is cheaper.
那家便宜
Are you joking? They're terrible.
你耍我 那家最坑
Nothing fresh.
又不新鲜
I meant
我说是
the fish stall behind it.
后面那个鱼档
It's cheap.
便宜
You're right.
是啊
Not to mention
尤其是
the owner's dad is a good man.
小老板的爸爸人也很好
Ten dollars.
算你十块钱
It's unfortunate
就有点可惜
how sudden he passed.
走得太突然了
Heart attack.
心脏病
Asthma.
哮喘
Your daughter’s all grown up.
女儿长那么大
Doesn’t she want to move out?
都没有搬出去
Her mom left me because of my gambling.
年轻时候好赌就离婚了
After her mom
她妈妈
died from illness,
病了走了之后
she moved in with me.
就把她搬来这边跟我住了
Thanks.
谢谢
What are you doing?
你干什么呢
Planning to work in a casino?
想到赌场找工作吗
Selling fish doesn't pay the bills
卖鱼不够养家糊口
Give me a grass carp.
来个草鱼
See these calluses?
你看我手上的茧子
Got them from playing cards when I was young.
年轻的时候练牌练的
I wanted to be a God of Gamblers.
一心想做赌神
I didn't know
结果
that was only in the movies.
只有电影中出现
I thought
你不说
you got callus from holding guns.
我还以为你握枪呢
Never held a gun.
枪我就没握过
Held a chef's knife for 10 years, though.
抓菜刀做了十几年
Let's find a time.
不如改天
I'll cook a few dishes.
做几个小菜
Come over
有空来我家
and have a drink.
喝点小酒
That's funny.
那么巧
I was a chef when I was abroad.
我在海外的时候也当过厨师
My teacher was from Hangzhou.
我师傅是个杭州人
I make a mean West Lake vinegar fish.
我的西湖醋鱼
How about today?
择日不如撞日
Great.
好
I happen to have a bottle of Chilean wine
刚好我家里也有一瓶智利干白
that goes with that dish.
跟醋鱼很搭
You bring the wine, I'll cook.
你带酒 我煮菜
Come in.
请进
Have a seat.
您随便坐
I'll put this into the fridge.
我把这个冰起来
What was he doing?
他在干嘛
Checking for dust.
摸摸灰尘
To see if they just moved in.
看看他们是不是刚搬进来
You're not getting away.
你跑不掉的
You may be the guest,
虽然你是客
but you're not spared from kitchen duty.
下厨做菜你跑不掉的
Show us what you've got.
露一手吧
I can't wait.
很期待啊
How long were you a chef for?
你当了多少年厨
Over ten years.
十多年了
And that's the knife you use?
就用这样的刀啊
You know your knives.
你很会用刀
I just like
我只想
doing things the right way.
把事情做对
Got any kids?
你有孩子吗
I'm on my own.
我就一个人
A lonely old man.
一个孤独老人
Here's a home-cooked meal.
你现在不是有家宴了吗
Your girl seems like a smart kid.
你小孩看起来挺聪明的
That scar on her forehead...
她额头上那个疤
How'd she get it?
是怎么弄的
Put that phone away.
别吃饭老抱着个电话
Talk with our guest instead.
跟叔叔聊聊天
Okay.
好
I need the bathroom.
我上个厕所
If I had a child,
我要是有小孩的话
I'd ban phones from the dinner table, too.
我也不会让他在饭桌上玩手机
Start coloning.
已经开始拷贝
What are you studying?
你上学念什么专业的
Nursing.
护理
You plan to be a nurse after graduation?
那毕业以后就当护士了
Maybe in a retirement home.
去养老院吧可能
What a kind heart.
有爱心
How'd you get that scar?
你这个是怎么弄的
This one?
这个
Fifth grade.
小学五年级
Got into a fight with some girls.
跟几个女生打架弄的
Why were you fighting?
你还打架
A classmate was being bullied.
她们当时欺负另一个女生
Couldn't stand idly by.
我看不过
But I never told anyone that until now.
不过我到现在都没跟别人说过这事
Does your dad know?
那你跟你老爸呢
He couldn’t possibly know.
他怎么可能知道
That’s odd.
那就奇怪了
What’s up?
怎么了
How'd she get that scar again?
你说你小孩那个疤怎么弄的
She got into a fight in fifth grade.
五年级跟一堆小孩子打架
One against five.
一打五
Someone bashed her with a bottle.
给人家拿个瓶子磕的
I never told anyone.
我没跟别人说过
Not even my mom.
我妈都不知道
You didn’t tell her because
你怕你妈妈担心
you didn't want her to worry.
你怎么会跟她说
Even your teacher
连老师
thought you hit a door.
都认为她撞在门上
Right?
对不对
How'd you know, then?
那你怎么知道的
After our divorce,
我跟你妈离婚之后
my debts
因为赌债
made me some enemies.
得罪了一些人
I was worried they'd hurt you.
怕他们伤害你
The truth is...
其实
I was always nearby.
我一直都在
See?
你看
That's a dad.
这才是老爸
Then why didn’t you help me?
那你怎么不帮我
Help you?
我还帮你
Remember what you did to those girls?
你忘了你把人家打成什么样了
It's horrifying.
太恐怖了
I was too scared to step in.
我自己女儿我都不敢上前拉
Give me some credit.
给我点面子好不好
I was standing up for someone.
我见义勇为好吗
You were...
你那是
What?
什么 什么
You were committing murder.
你那个是杀人灭口
Com'on now.
什么呀
You're embarrassing me.
你让我好尴尬
How'd it go?
怎么样
Go on.
去吧
Thank you.
谢谢
What for?
谢什么
For protecting us.
谢谢你保护我们
Some things
有些事情
can never be mended.
一辈子弥补不了
The only thing I could do for your father
我能替你父亲做的就是
was to watch over you.
好好保护你们
I know you've been worrying about me.
我知道你一直放心不下我
You want to protect me.
老护着我
But I’ve grown up.
但可能我也长大了
I'll be okay.
我会OK的
You're okay.
你OK的
Big Brother...
哥
If you fail,
如果你失败
what happens next
后面的事
will be my call.
就要听我的
If we do it your way,
真按你那想法去做
there's no turning back for us.
我们就没有回头路了
I just want to
我只是想
do things the right way.
把事情做对
They have anti-tracking.
对方有反追踪
Must be that hacker.
应该是那个黑客
Stand down.
不追了
Have you checked their background?
那对父女的底细你查了吗
I have.
查了
Guoguo?
果果
Forgot something?
忘东西了
Nothing to worry about.
没什么可担心的
Maybe I did worry too much.
那可能是我多虑了
Did you
你是不是
sense something's off?
察觉到什么了
I realize that
我察觉到
you're a big boy now.
你长大了
It really is time to let go.
是时候该放手了
Let's follow through with your plan.
就按你的计划进行
Got it.
知道了
You know what you're doing?
有把握吗
I do.
放心吧
That girl isn't Guoguo.
这女孩好像不是果果
What do you mean?
什么意思
There’s something wrong with this feed.
这画面有问题
That’s definitely not Qiuguo.
这女孩肯定不是果果
Send backup to Wong.
昌宁二队支援黄警官
He's in danger.
黄警官有危险
Cops are coming, leave.
警察来了 快走
I failed.
失败了
I'll find another way.
我再想办法
Hey.
喂
Has the Shadow moved?
影子有没有动静
Nope, all quiet.
没有 一切如常
You had your chance, Xiwang.
给你机会了 哥
Those boys
这帮孩子
didn’t even tell the Shadow
竟然没有直接告诉影子
that he’s being watched.
他被盯上了
They know we'd use the Shadow to track them,
算准了我们会利用影子顺藤摸瓜
so we wouldn't touch him.
根本不会动他
Killing me and creating chaos
杀死我 制造混乱
would've created an opening to break The Shadow out.
趁机把影子从我们眼皮底下救走
After failing this time,
那这次失败后
they'll look for another chance.
他们一定还会再找机会的
Their chance is our opportunity, too.
他们的机会就是我们的机会
We have to nail this gang of thieves
必须揪出这几个同伙
once for all.
一网打尽
Shadow's on the move.
影子移动
Surveillance team, spread out.
跟踪队拉开距离
Madam, that's the same taxi as the one at Aoxing.
长官 这辆出租经过比对 跟澳兴大厦是同一辆
Sending photo to the surveillance team now.
已经把司机照片同步给跟踪队了
We’re standing by.
我们已准备就绪
When the suspects' location is locked,
跟踪队锁定位置后
we're ready to move in.
我们会实施抓捕
Target vehicle is approaching our HQ.
目标车辆即将途经总部大楼前
Are they turning themselves in?
是不是打算送他去自首
Doesn’t look like it.
看来没有这个打算
Wait.
等一下
Show me that cabinet again.
柜里的东西再让我看一下
Why is that still there?
这东西怎么还在这
It's unsolvable.
这题无解
They're all wrong.
都是错的
Get closer, show me again.
你拉近一下给我看一下
What’s that?
怎么回事
It seems Wong's van has been hit.
黄警官的车好像被什么东西给撞了
Officer Wong?
黄警官
Wong, can you hear me?
黄警官 能听到吗
Wong, come in if you hear me.
黄警官 收到请回复
Officer Wong?
黄警官
Guoguo.
果果
Their...
他们
Their vehicles broke in.
他们的车已经冲进来了
Whose vehicles?
谁的车
HQ is under attack?
总部遇袭
Madam, what's going on?
长官 现在什么情况
Du Ping,
杜平
ready the mobile command unit.
移动指挥台准备
Yes, ma'am.
收到
Surveillance, stay focused.
跟踪队注意力集中
Eyes on target.
打起精神
Watch the Shadow's every move.
把影子给我盯死了
Officer Wong.
黄警官
Someone's still alive.
车里还有活人
Terminate.
杀掉
The phone...
电话
It's smashed.
碎了
The key to the puzzle isn't the numbers.
六宫格上面的重点不是数字
it’s the positions.
是位置
They’re using Braille.
他们使用的是盲文
The bubble wrap is also Braille.
气泡膜上也是盲文
Get Intelligence to decipher the messages.
得让情报部门破解上面的信息
Find out what they're up to.
查查他们的目标到底是什么
Find a phone, I'll hold them back.
你找电话 我拖住他们
Go.
走
What's this place?
这是什么地方
Looks like an abandoned orphanage.
好像是个废弃的孤儿院
No other suspect in sight.
没有见到其它匪徒
Use thermal to follow Shadow.
用热成像跟住影子
I need eyes on the inside.
我要看到里面的情况
Captain.
伍耀磊
In the orphanage!
孤儿院里面
HQ.
总部
This is Alpaca.
我是羊驼
Can anyone hear me?
有人听到吗
Command central?
指挥中心
We've lost all comms.
我们这边全部断联了
Brothers, get to work.
兄弟们 开工了
Chop him up.
打包带走
Do you know how many cops came after me?
你们知道当时多少警察抓我吗
Two hundred.
两百
If I took off,
马上跑
I’d be dead for sure.
一定死
So what did you do?
那你是怎么做的
The idiot who got nailed
我把被盯上那个笨蛋
became bait.
当诱饵
Then I took out the biggest threat
先干掉警察里头
in the Police Force.
最具威胁的那个
That took out the cops' eyes.
那警察就没有了眼睛
Then I took out the idiot,
顺手再把那个笨蛋也给做了
cutting off the cops' ears, too.
那警察就没有了耳朵
I've become the idiot in my boys' eyes.
我成了孩子们眼中的笨蛋
However...
不过
first you need to be sure to have
你得先有把握能做掉
what it takes.
才行
You're a big boy now.
你长大了
You know what you're doing?
有把握吗
Who do you think I am?
瞧不起谁
Kill him.
弄死他
Cell signal's jammed.
手机信号被屏蔽了
Find a sat phone to call for backup.
寻找卫星电话呼叫增援
We'll go buy some time.
我们去争取时间
That's him.
就是他
Gotta kill him to get paid.
不杀他拿不到钱
The Shadow sends messages via Braille.
影子用盲文传递信息
The bubble wrap and sudoku are all Braille.
气泡膜和数独上都是盲文
Guoguo.
果果
Give that intel to Madam Wang.
快告诉王长官
How did the cops arrive so quickly?
信号都屏蔽了 警察增援怎么这么快
Madam, we've got this.
长官 让我们来
Godfather.
干爹
I failed.
失败了
I'll find another way.
我再想办法
You had your chance, Xiwang.
给你机会了 哥
If we're the ones nailed by the police,
换作如果是我们被警察盯死了
what would the old man do?
他会怎么做
This is no one's fault.
谁也别怪谁
It's just
要怪
carelessness and bad luck.
就怪他自己太大意了
Simon’s idea?
是他的主意
Mine.
我的
Still think you're not like me?
还说你不像我
Xiwang,
哥
what are you doing?
你上去干嘛
You don’t understand
你不了解
how dangerous this man is.
这个人的恐怖
Leave.
离开这
This isn't part of the plan.
这不是我们的计划
The old man has to die here
老头子必须死在这
for you to be safe.
你们才安全
Leave.
快离开
This isn't part of the plan.
这不是我们的计划
This was always my plan.
这一直就是哥的计划
I'm helping you for the last time.
最后一次帮你了
You want to die?
命都不要了
Simon's my little brother.
熙蒙是弟弟
If he screws up...
他错
It's my job to fix it.
也得我兜着
I have no choice.
我没得选
Then I'll send you on your way.
那我就送你一程
Godfather.
干爹
Your life
你的命
ends here too.
也得留在这
Get ready.
准备
He’s a wolf.
他是狼
We’re wolf pups.
我们是狼崽子
He's our father.
他是爸爸
In my next life,
熙旺下辈子
I hope I'll be your real son.
给你当亲儿子
Take care of them.
做好善后
Look after their families.
安慰好他们家人
Yes, sir.
是
Kandam, it's me.
钢蛋 是我
Gundam.
钢蛋
Like the robot.
高达
What do we know?
有什么进展
I just contacted Captain Wu.
刚联系上伍警官
A big explosion at the orphanage.
孤儿院发生爆炸
The Shadow?
影子呢
Not sure.
暂不清楚
But we've ID'd the assailants.
但查到袭击者身份了
On the surface,
这几个人表面上
they're private security
是受雇于私人安保公司
for VIP clients at casinos.
给赌场 VIP 客户做保镖
But they also moonlight as mercenaries,
但私底下也是在暗网上
taking high-risk jobs on the dark web.
接高危武装行动的雇佣兵
Alpaca contacted Evidence
羊驼收到小猪讯息的时候
after receiving Piggy's message.
就联系了物证科
We'll have the results soon, thanks to him.
多亏了他 应该马上就有结果
It's Gordon D.
是段志鸿
Why is Duan's HK$10 billion
为什么段志鸿的一百亿港币
in the police station's server?
会在警局的服务器里面
Without the decryption keys,
因为我们没有密钥
the loot can only be kept as digital evidence.
这笔赃款只能当作数字物证储存
The only way to access the cold wallet
如果想要进入账户
is by using its digital key,
需要密钥程序
enabling the 12-word passphrase
把十二位单词密码
to be inputted with nanosecond precision.
按预设好的纳秒区间精准输入
They were here.
他们得手了
Madam,
长官
leave this to us.
这里交给我们
Be careful.
小心点
We have a report of a robbery.
接到资产管理中心报案
Suspects just left.
劫匪刚刚离开
Four males, all in early 20s.
四名男性 约二十出头
It was those SWAT guys just now.
就是刚才那几个特警
The perps cut the power to
盗匪切断电源
stop us from shutting the hacker out remotely.
就是为了非法入侵时防止我们远程切断
They need a local network
自设局域网需要在特定的
within range to access the servers.
距离范围内才能接入
What does that mean?
什么意思
The hacker was just here.
那个黑客刚刚也在这
We were wrong.
我们错了
What did we do wrong?
我们有什么错
The old man got himself caught.
老头子自己被盯上
Like an idiot.
像个笨蛋一样
He was outsmarted by the cops.
被警察耍得团团转
That cop’s house was too clean.
那个警察的家里太干净了
It didn't even have a router.
连路由器都没有
It was absurd.
这不正常
No way the old man didn't notice.
老头子怎么可能没发现
But he still played along.
他还继续陪着警察玩
What are you trying to say?
你在说什么
I think
他可能
he was actually throwing
其实是想帮我们
the cops off our trail.
引开警察
The 'Ghost Car' trap?
鬼车陷阱吗
He's not that noble.
他没有那么伟大
He's the most cunning,
他是世界上最狡猾
ruthless,
最心狠手辣
and...
最
He's a dad.
他是爸爸
Get a grip.
振作点
Get away first.
跑得掉
Then we'll cry.
再难过
We lost a SWAT vehicle at
我们发现有一辆特警车辆
the surveillance blind spot on Calcada do Carmo.
在嘉伯中巷监控盲区消失
It's likely the thieves will flee tonight.
盗匪今晚离境机率很大
Watch every possible exit route
排查全部可能途径
and all scheduled departures.
和预定离境人员名单
Every route?
全部途径
That'll take time.
这可能要花点时间
We don’t have time.
我们没有时间
What do we do now?
现在怎么办
Activate S.P.A.I.S.,
启动 S.P.A.I.S.
restore analysis and command authority.
恢复自主分析权和指令执行权
Copy.
收到
Have her study the thieves' past MO
让她马上学习盗匪之前的作案资料
and predict their next moves.
分析接下来的行为轨迹
Show her their most recent methods, too.
把刚才的作案手段也同步给她学习
If possible...
如果可能的话
Madam.
长官
Spice Girl's got a lead.
辣妹有结果了
That fast?
这么快
The suspect vehicle disappeared on Calcada do Carmo.
嫌疑人车辆在嘉伯中巷监控盲区消失后
Within a three-kilometer radius,
三公里范围内
a gray van was caught on cameras.
监控拍到的这辆灰色面包车
There’s a 67% chance
有百分之六十七的可能性
that the thieves switched to this van.
为盗匪更换车辆
There's an 82% chance the thieves are
他们有百分之八十二的可能性
headed to the Wynn Palace.
去永利皇宫酒店
Wynn?
永利
The Wynn again?
怎么又是永利
I told you to learn,
我让你学习
not copy old answers.
没让你抄作业
Don’t move.
别动
Hands on your head.
双手抱头
Put down the knife.
把刀放下
- Put it down. -Put down the knife.
-放下 -把刀放下
Freeze.
别动
Ting.
唐婷
The Shadow's still alive.
影子还活着
On your knees.
跪地
Hands on your head.
双手抱头
Daddy.
老爸
On your knees.
跪地
Hands on your head.
双手抱头
On your knees. Hands on your head.
跪下 双手抱头
On your knees.
跪下
Wynn Palace.
永利皇宫
Take me there.
带我过去
There’s someone you haven’t seen.
有一个你们没见过
I'll point him out.
我帮你指认
Spice Girl found a vehicle
辣妹找到辆与出境途径
relevant to a possible exit route
有大概率关联的嫌疑车辆
that leads to suspicious individuals.
最终排查到可疑人员
Suspicious in identities?
身份可疑
No.
不是
In the number of them.
是数量
The Wynn has an art exhibition.
永利有个画展
The paintings are flying back to Paris tonight.
今晚结束之后展品会上飞机飞回巴黎
Six Chinese personnel were added
前两天名单里面
to the manifest two days ago.
多出六名中方随行人员
And on the night of the last heist,
另外上次作案当晚
Wynn also had art pieces set to leave.
永利展品有同样离境计划
This Spice Girl's gifted.
这个辣妹有点东西
Cops are here.
警察到了
That's fast.
这么快
Plan B.
备用撤离方案
Doghead here.
我是狗头
X Target may be in the laundry room.
疑似X Target进了洗衣房
Piggy, laundry room south door.
小猪 洗衣房南侧还有一个门
Get over there.
去堵他
Copy.
收到
What's Surveillance's ETA?
跟踪队还有多久到
Leave him to us, you go.
这里交给我们 你先走
Piggy.
小猪
X Target has left the laundry room.
X Target从洗衣房溜走了
Lil Puppy and Pretty Face
小奶狗和大漂亮
are showing off their moves here.
在这边才艺展示呢
I'll have a chat with them.
我会试着跟他们好好聊聊
Try to get them to surrender.
争取让他们自首
Surrender, my ass.
自首你个粑粑
Attention, all units.
各单位注意
Wynn Palace South Lawn is packed with people.
永利皇宫南边草坪广场聚集了很多人
There seems to be an event tonight.
今晚应该是有什么活动
Scratch that.
更正一下
It’s Mad Puppy and Psycho Puss.
是小疯狗跟神经喵
Piggy to Doghead.
小猪呼叫狗头
Go, Piggy.
小猪 说
I'm at the party.
我在草坪派对了
I think he's here,
我觉得他就在这
but I can't find him.
但我根本找不到他
Stay calm.
冷静一点
Doghead to Animal Paradise.
呼叫萌宠乐园
Use the Shadow's number to call him.
用影子的号码给他打电话
A.I. voice imitation?
AI仿声吗
Let the old man talk to them.
让老家伙直接跟他说
Copy.
收到
Godfather?
干爹
Xiwang died for nothing.
我哥白死了
Tracing X Target's phone now.
开始追踪X Target的手机了
There is no anti-tracking.
没有反跟踪
He's not hiding anymore.
他没想藏了
Piggy.
小猪
Focus.
注意力集中
Observe people's reactions.
看所有人的反应
Copy.
是
Simon,
熙蒙
the police are fishing for you.
警察在钓你
If the police catch you today,
如果你今天被警察抓到
I'll be very disappointed.
我会很失望的
I may have disappointed you already.
可能已经让你失望了
You had a good plan today.
你今天的计划很好
I like it.
我很欣赏
Thank you, Godfather.
谢谢你 干爹
But...
但是
Anyone who knows what they're doing
想要做事有把握
would finish things themselves.
必须自己动手
Noted.
记住了
In this regard,
这方面
Xiwang did a better job.
阿旺做得比你好
I was really hoping you'd all be able
我希望你们都能过上
to live the life you wanted.
你们想要的生活
This is my last time helping you.
最后一次帮你了
Shadow was stalling on purpose.
影子在故意拖延时间
There is a chance to identify him
要转移就有破绽
if he tries to move.
这是个机会
Piggy.
小猪
Remember the key points of tracking?
你还记得跟踪时候的记忆要点吗
Find prominent and permanent features.
抓突出且不变特征
It's okay if your memory's fuzzy.
记忆模糊没关系
When you see those features,
特征再次出现
Your brain will kick in to help.
大脑会帮你想起来
I see him.
我发现他了
He's...
他好像
Hello?
喂
Let me out.
放我出去
Madam,
长官
Piggy's not answering,
小猪还是联系不上
Potsticker and Tofu are on-site.
锅贴 豆花他们到现场了
We need X Target's features.
需要X Target的特征信息
Too many people at the party.
派对上太多人了
Everyone looks like X Target to me now.
我现在看谁都像X Target
Your X Target is 180 cm tall
你们的X Target身高一八零
and weighs 68 kg.
体重六十八公斤
Long hair.
长发
That's Wu Yaolei's comms.
这是伍耀磊的通讯设备
He's sneaking into the VIP area.
他要溜进VIP区了
Animal Paradise, is the intel solid?
呼叫萌宠乐园 信息可信吗
Cut him off.
切断
Take my earpiece.
耳机给你
I'll grab another from the car.
我再去车里拿
Report your position.
赶快报告位置
They're worried about you.
他们很担心你
Shadow just ID'd X Target.
影子刚刚已经指认了X Target
Don't worry.
放心
Him and the driver are twins.
他跟那个司机是双胞胎
Piggy to Animal Paradise.
小猪呼叫萌宠乐园
Sorry for making you worried.
让你们担心了
I'm glad you're okay.
没事就好
Found anything?
有什么发现
The target and the driver are twins.
目标跟那个司机是双胞胎
VIP area, I may have found him.
VIP区 我好像看见他了
Who are you?
你谁啊
Sorry.
对不起
Should've never trusted Shadow.
就不该相信影子
He had his reasons.
一定有原因
Everyone, report your position.
所有人 报告位置
Tofu, south entrance.
豆花 南口
Potsticker, north entrance.
锅贴 北口
Pork Bun, north side of the dance floor.
猪扒包 舞池北侧
Rice Noodle and Lucky, laundry room.
肠粉 旺财在洗衣房
Alpaca.
羊驼
Where's Alpaca?
羊驼呢
He gave me his earpiece, he went to get another.
他把耳机给我之后回车里拿新的去了
No new comm device activated.
没有新的通讯设备启动
His badge's GPS shows
他证件上的GPS显示
he's headed to
他正走向
Cotai East LRT station.
路氹东站轻轨站
Him and the driver are twins!
他跟那个司机是双胞胎
Did you mean to...?
你本来是不是想
Doesn't matter now.
不重要了
Fragile.
脆弱
Lucky.
幸运
Relax.
放松
Energy.
能量
Target.
目标
Amateur.
生手
Family.
家族
Shadow.
影子
Betrayal.
背叛
Grateful.
感激
Blind.
目盲
The times have changed.
时代不同
But rules are rules.
规矩还是规矩
Simon...
熙蒙
Farewell.
好走
He's dead!
杀人了
Madam, Officer Wong,
长官 黄警官
we just caught the other two.
我们刚刚抓到另外两个
Without Shadow's direction,
没有影子指挥
they had nowhere to hide.
他们根本没地方躲
How's it going?
你们那边怎么样
Madam, Officer Wong...
长官 黄警官
Liu Jinxiao.
刘锦肖
The artery was cut.
动脉被划开了
Guoguo,
果果
press his wound.
压住伤口
Don't let him move.
别让他动
Black cap,
黑色帽子
dark blue jacket,
深蓝色外套
black jeans.
黑色牛仔裤
Jinxiao.
刘锦肖
Don't you sleep.
刘锦肖 别睡
Ambulance.
救护车 救护车
I understand how you feel,
心情可以理解
but there's another unit assigned to follow up.
但在逃人员有专门的警力负责
We have a new assignment now.
而且我们有新任务
Then I'm taking leave.
那我申请休假
I need some time off, personal reasons.
个人原因 需要调整状态
What are you doing here?
你怎么来了
Wu sent this retiree
伍警官让我这个退休的
to keep someone on leave company.
来陪陪你这个放假的
Eat up.
吃吧
Thanks.
谢了
What's the status?
什么情况
No leads.
没线索
It’s like the Shadow vanished into thin air.
影子依旧人间蒸发一样
Money.
钱
It always leaves a trail,
任何时候都是线索
especially in a case like this.
尤其是这种案子
This is where the first victim's crypto
这是第一受害人汪杰的加密货币
was transferred out to.
被转出来的所在位置
Those boys confessed that
据他们交代
only two people know the password.
这个密码只有两个人知道
One of them is dead.
现在一个人已经死了
And the money hasn’t moved, right?
钱没动过是吧
Not a cent.
没有
Do you remember
那你还记得
what I told you about
我跟你说过
what kind of thief
傅隆生
the Shadow is?
是什么样的贼吗
Old-timer.
老派的贼
Old school.
传统手段
I know nothing about this stuff,
这玩意我一窍不通
and I’m guessing
很有可能
he doesn't, either.
他也一样
He’s still a man of that era.
他还是那个时代的人
What do you think he'll do?
你认为他会怎么做呢
He's clueless about cashing out crypto.
他根本不知道怎么提现
Fu was an old-school thief.
傅隆生是老派的贼
His MO back in the day
他早年惯用的作案手段
was robbing jewelry stores
就是打劫金铺或者首饰店
and getting victims to buy back the loot
然后让受害人赎回自己的物品
to spare the trouble of fencing them.
免除销赃的繁琐
This is all he knows.
他只认识这个
Let's eat.
吃饭吧
No time.
吃什么
Let’s go.
走啊
Why not take the door?
干嘛不走门
Why take the door?
干嘛要走门
Sophia, where are you?
索菲亚 你在哪
Where's my milk?
我的牛奶呢
It's been days already.
好几天了
Did I get it wrong?
我们会不会判断有误
Trust your instincts.
相信你的直觉
Blame me if it's wrong.
错了算我的
That's what I planned to do.
有这个打算
I’ve been thinking these past few days.
这几天我一直在想一个问题
Carrying out the mission is our duty.
执行任务是天职
But having blood, emotion,
但有血有肉
and a heart...
有心
That's our nature.
这是天性
Being a cop shouldn’t strip that away.
当警察的职责绝不该凌驾在这之上
So, back then...
所以当年的你
You did nothing wrong.
没有做错
Police.
警察
Everyone out.
你们都出去
I know you want to make up a story,
我知道你想编故事
but don't turn yourself into an accomplice.
但我希望你不要把自己变成共犯
Fu asked Wang for 10 million in cash
傅隆生让汪杰出一千万现金
for the account password.
买账户密码
The meet's at Tin Seng Tea House.
他们约在路环天星茶舍
I'll notify Captain Wu.
我通知伍耀磊
Don’t move until we get there.
到了你再行动
Wu, what’s your ETA?
伍耀磊 还有多久能到
Ten minutes.
十分钟
Officer Wong?
黄警官呢
Under 5 minutes.
五分钟之内
We've tapped Qiuguo's phone.
我们正在监听何秋果电话
Copy.
收到
Sound check.
声音测试
Loud and clear.
收到 清晰
Wang is already 10 minutes late.
汪杰已经超过约定时间十分钟
He'll leave at any moment.
他应该随时会走
He's leaving.
他要走了
Hi.
您好
Use the front door next time.
这里不能走 下次走前面
Small world.
这么巧
Alone?
一个人
You have the wrong person.
你认错人了吧
You don't know me?
不认识我了
We had dinner together.
一起吃过一顿饭
Forgotten me already?
那么快就忘记了
Do you need something?
先生 你有事吗
I'm so moved.
感动啊
It's you. Uncle.
是你啊 叔叔
What's with the outfit?
你怎么穿成这样
That hair of yours
你这头发
freaked me out.
吓死我了
I thought you were some creepy old guy
我刚刚还以为哪个变态大叔
trying to hit on me.
过来跟我搭讪呢
Sorry for scaring you.
吓着你了
I apologize.
不好意思
No problem.
没事
You were leaving.
看你准备要走
Were you planning to tail me?
是不是要继续跟踪我
All by yourself?
就凭你一个人
Pardon?
抱歉 我
What are you talking about?
不明白你在说什么
A few days ago,
几天前
you were at Wynn.
你在永利
You were with a boy.
还跟一个男孩在一起
Where's that boy now?
那个男孩呢
Dead.
死了
Broke up?
分手了
Didn’t you hear me?
我说话你听不明白
He’s dead.
人死了
Team two.
二组到达现场后
Seal Ponte Cais de Coloane and R. dos Navegantes.
控制路环码头和船人街
Team three, take Entre-Campos, Cordoaria and Cheoc Van.
三组田畔街打缆街和竹湾马路路口
He was killed in an LRT station.
在轻轨站被人捅死了
That boy was a cop,
他就是一个警察
and so are you.
你也是
You’re crazy.
你有病啊
Get away from me.
能不能离我远点
Go away.
走开啊
You've managed to stall me.
能拖我那么久
Kiddo...
孩子
You're pretty good.
你可以
Guoguo.
果果
Call an ambulance.
叫救护车
Police.
警察
Get out of here.
走 走
Please use the front door.
麻烦你走正门
Liked my West Lake vinegar fish?
我做的西湖醋鱼好吃吗
It sucked.
难吃死了
Go to hell.
那你就去死吧
Join me.
一起呀
Come on.
来啊
Com'on.
来
Guoguo.
果果
Are you all right?
你怎么样
It's not deep.
刀口不深
I'll be fine.
没事
Backup is almost here.
救援马上就到
Earpiece is in the pocket.
耳机在口袋
Guoguo...
你
Go after him.
放手去吧
Target headed out front door.
目标出正门
Wig and black jacket.
假发 黑色外套
I'm going after him.
我去跟他
Piggy, he's heading north.
小猪 他往北边走了
There's no surveillance in the alley.
这条街没有其他监控
You have to find him yourself.
你得找到他
Possible suspect sighting.
发现疑似目标
It's not the Shadow.
不是影子
The roads are a mess,
这里路好乱
I can't find him.
我找不到他
Qiuguo, stay calm.
何秋果 冷静点
Get it together.
打起精神
I can't find him.
找不到
Piggy,
小猪
backup's almost there.
支援马上就到
He can't be far.
他跑不远的
You got this.
我们需要你
Remember the key points of tracking?
还记得跟踪的基本要领吗
He Qiuguo?
何秋果
Watch
看
and memorize.
跟记
You only get one glance.
只看一眼
Focus on key points.
抓重点看
All by yourself?
就凭你一个人
Memorize.
记
Memorize actively first.
一开始 主动记忆
Where's the boy?
那男孩呢
Over time...
慢慢的
Broke up?
分手了
...You'll start to memorize subconsciously.
就会无意识的自动储存
Go after him.
放手去吧
Hand.
手
Bandage.
绷带
Target spotted.
发现目标
I got him.
我找着他了
Where are you?
你在哪
An alley south on R. do Meio
在中街往南的巷子里
Wu, prepare for arrest.
伍耀磊 立即制定抓捕方案
We're here.
我们到了
Sir, you can't take painkillers like that.
先生 止痛药不能这么吃
Guoguo.
果果
You got this.
加油啊
Wait.
等一下
Qiuguo,
何秋果
if I set a trap at the Chapel of St. Francis Xavier,
如果我在圣堂广场布置个口袋
can you send him this way?
你能不能把嫌犯送进来
Captain,
报告
I can't do this alone.
我一个人搞不定
I need my team.
需要我的团队
I need the Surveillance Team.
我需要跟踪队
Piggy.
小猪
Miss us?
想我们了吗
Central,
报告
Pork Bun is in position.
猪扒包就位
I'm at your 8 o'clock.
你八点钟方向
Potsticker in position.
锅贴已就位
Parallel street,
我在你隔壁街
3 o' clock.
三点钟方向
Eggy in position.
培根蛋就位
Tofu in position.
豆花就位
Nine o’clock, next street over.
隔壁街九点钟方向
Calling Animal Paradise,
报告萌宠乐园
Doghead is safe.
狗头安全
Rice Noodle in position.
肠粉就位
Two o’clock.
两点
I've studied and analyzed Shadow's habits.
经过总结影子的行为习惯
From the current point,
从当前起点
there are 165 possible escape routes.
他的路线选择有一百六十五种
17 of them reach the Chapel of St. Francis Xavier.
其中前往圣方济各圣堂广场的路线为十七种
Pudding in position.
布丁就位
Right behind you.
我在你正后方
Lucky in position.
旺财就位
Directly ahead of target.
目标正前方
Coordinates and directions are sent to the team.
已同步萌宠小队坐标与信息
I will continue calculating his route choicecs,
我将实时整理路径
and you will be updated.
同步给各位
Doghead calling Animal Paradise.
狗头呼叫萌宠乐园
Adorable Unit's on-site.
萌宠小队到达现场
Alpaca in position.
羊驼就位
Calling Animal Paradise.
报告萌宠乐园
Piggy in position.
小猪就位
Attention, Adorable Unit,
萌宠小队注意
Chapel of St. Francis Xavier Square
圣方济各圣堂广场
is about 280 meters northwest
在目标现在位置的
of the target’s current location.
西北方向二百八十米左右
The Shadow's injured.
影子受伤了
He values his life.
他很惜命
All he wants right now is to flee.
他现在一定只想逃离这里
He won't risk getting shot to harm you.
不会冒险挨子弹跟你们纠缠的
Adorable Unit.
萌宠小队
You're the hounds now.
你们现在是猎犬
Round up and hunt.
准备围猎吧
Don't move.
别动 别动
Hands on your head.
双手抱头
I'm fine.
没事
I'm a cop.
我是警察
Fu Longsheng,
傅隆生
you're under arrest.
你被捕了
Madam
警官
He Qiuguo.
何秋果
You made this happen.
是你抓到我的
You cuff me.
就你来吧
What's so funny?
笑什么笑
You really can fight.
你是真会打架
Shut up.
闭嘴
Guoguo.
果果
Command central,
报告指挥中心
we have Fu Longsheng in custody.
抓获犯罪嫌疑人傅隆生
Well done.
干的不错
Your father
你爸爸
would be very proud.
一定会骄傲的
Sir.
黄警官
Requesting to join the interrogation.
申请参与审讯
Aren’t you on leave?
不休假了
Requesting to terminate my leave.
申请终止休假
I do miss work.
真想念当年工作的日子
We'll be needing your help in the future.
以后有问题还得请教您
I've already taught them
我的那一套
everything I know.
他们都学会了
I'm going back
我啊
to my retirement.
过我退休的生活去吧
Go to the hospital first.
您还是先去医院吧
Officer Wong.
黄警官
Why are we meeting here?
怎么选了这么个地方见面
We found a lead.
我们查到线索
That hacker, Simon,
那个叫熙蒙的黑客
had help from someone much more capable.
背后有更厉害的人在帮他
My people thought so, too.
我们也有同感
We checked his computer.
我们查了他的电脑
There is no hacking source code in his devices.
他的服务器里没有入侵源代码
The more important question is
更关键的问题是
why did this mastermind
他背后的人
deliberately leave loopholes for my people to find?
为什么要故意透露线索给我们查到
Wait.
等一下
I know who my people are.
我知道我们是谁
Your people are...
你们是
Right now,
现在
you don't have the clearance yet.
你没有权限知道
Are't you just a retired dogwalker?
您不就是个退休的遛狗老头嘛
You sound like you have a secret identity.
说的跟还有别人不知道的身份
Fragile.
脆弱
Lucky.
幸运
Relax.
放松
Energy.
能量
Target.
目标
Amateur.
生手
Family.
家族
Shadow.
影子
Betrayal.
背叛
Grateful.
感激
Blind.
目盲
Escalate.
升级